

Juan Antonio Montenegro

DATA SCIENTIST JR.



Profile

Data Science Masters graduate with a passion for data, problem solving, efficiency and computer vision.

I bring forth experience on working with databases. performing data analysis, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and creation of statistical reports.



Contact information

- Email: juanmonte795@gmail.com
- Github: github.com/juananmonte
- Cellphone: (+82) 010-5461-7263
- Address: 서울특별시 성북구 보국문로 59-11 (59-11 Bogukmun-ro, Seongbuk-gu, Seoul)



Education

KOOKMIN UNIVERSITY

Data Science Master's degree | August 2020 - July 2022

RAFAEL LANDIVAR UNIVERSITY

Bachelors degree in Economy | January 2014 - July 2018

[A]*] Languages

- Korean: Intermediate (TOPIK II: Level 3 140 points)
- English: Fluent (TOEFL: Level C1 108 points)
- · Spanish: Native

Work Experience

R&D ENGINEER CHOWIS Co. LTD. | South Korea | Nov 2021 - April 2012

- Train and deploy deep learning models. My contributions managed to obtain a 15% increase in accuracy.
- Receive, retrieve, clean and prepare data for training models. I managed to automate this process and reduce the time of it from one day to 2 hours.
- · Give input and feedback on data collection process, model training and customer experience. My ideas managed to save time and correct mistakes improving the customer's experience by 10% (on reviews).
- Prepare scientific documentation and statistical monthly reports.

DATA ANALYST VESTEX-OEC | Guatemala | Jan 2017 - July 2019

- · Query, clean, analyze and present data for management.
- · Determine optimal data variables and relations to use for analysis. With my analysis, I proposed the creation of a statistical premium service for customers that could increase the organization's income by 20%.
- · Gather structured and unstructured datasets from internal and external databases.
- Create easy to understand and interactive data visualizations.

🗶 Skills

- Knowledge of Python, R, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ORACLE SQL Developer, ORACLE BI Suite, Git, Power BI, Microsoft Office programs, Linux.
- · Machine Learning and Deep Learning libraries and deployment (Tensorflow-Keras, Pytorch-Detectron, ...).
- Computer Vision knowledge (CV2, Imutils, ArUco, face recognition, ...)
- Strong background on statistics and data analysis / visualization.
- Great analytical and communication skills.
- Effective time management, leadership skills, efficient and fast learner.



Projects

SECURITY CAMERA APP

Creation of a web app for a security camera that can detect: faces, people, movement and up to types of crimes with 80% of accuracy using CV2, Flask and Yolov5.

BOXING ANALYTICS AND SELF-TRAINING APP

Creating an app that performs pose estimation and compares results with a database of the same movements done by professionals. Use of Tensorflow, Yolov5, CV2, Kivy and LabelMe.